TERRENCE MAHNKEN

Mount Juliet, TN 37122

Phone: 865.789.7867 | Email: terrencemm2@gmail.com LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/terrencemahnken | Portfolio: terrence.codes

SUMMARY

Dedicated and passionate software engineer with over a decade of experience in the technology sector across various industries. Driven by a mission to help people and solve problems. A strong advocate of teamwork, empathy, education, and quality. Recognized by colleagues for excellent organizational and communication skills and taking personal ownership of projects.

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

Senior Software Engineer

2023 - Current

CoStar Group

Nashville, TN

- Enhanced, maintained, and refactored several client-facing micro-frontend web applications built with React, Typescript, and GraphQL within a monorepo codebase.
- Optimized development speed by reducing compilation and build times by 50% by migrating build tools from Lerna to Turbo.
- Optimized front-end performance by reducing data loading times by 66% using GraphQL schema reduction technique, fragments, and caching.
- Built and enhanced .NET 6 web APIs and services using LINQ, writing dedicated SQL functions in PostgreSQL, and documenting using Swagger.
- Evangelized unit testing by setting up Jest for front-end testing and writing back-end tests using NUnit.

Front End Software Engineer

2021 - 2023

Data Skrive

Seattle, WA (Remote)

- Enhanced, maintained, and refactored internal front-end "portal" built with React, Material UI, Mobx,
 React Table, and Webpack using code construction best practices.
- Established front-end code construction standards and test-driven development (TDD) using Jest,
 Testing Library, GitLab CI, ESlint, Prettier, Husky, and VS Code tools and extensions.
- Collaborated with end-users and designers to develop custom React components using Storybook using the Component Driven Design (CDD) methodology.
- Led front-end engineering team of yearly tech debt planning and strategy, training, and code reviews.
- Wrote regression tests in Java using Selenium, Cucumber, and Gherkin.
- Dockerized and deployed the front end to AWS Fargate using Terraform.
- Implemented and tuned Datadog Real User Monitoring & Logging to provide usage statistics.
- Improved internal "portal" front-end using Lighthouse, Nginx, and refactoring practices to speed up build and deployments by 50%.

Senior Application Engineer

2021 - 2021

HCA Healthcare

Nashville, TN

- Maintained and improved Vue 2/Vuex application deployed to Microsoft IIS and used by 50k+ nurses and nurse leaders at 180+ facilities. Integrations with Tableau and ServiceNow.
- Migrated on-premise Vue/Node application to Microsoft Azure (Azure Functions, App Insights, CosmosDB)
- Maintained and improved React/Redux nursing application deployed to Azure and used at 56 facilities.
- Maintained, improved, and troubleshot Node services and scripts for data ingestion and Swagger APIs.
- Implemented and supported JavaScript TV application used on 12k+ LG TVs in patient rooms at 67 facilities to display patient data from Meditech and Compnutrition.

CODING FOR CAREGIVERS (HCA INTERNAL HACK-A-THON)

 Worked with a team of 20 to develop a proof-of-concept, Angular/.NET-based web application using AWS Comprehend and Transcribe Medical allowing medical staff to dictate patient vitals, comments, and notes quickly. Ellucian Nashville, TN

- Implemented, administered, and built out front-end, internal user portal and identity and access management system used by all 50k+ faculty, staff, and students within the Tennessee Board of Regents system office and the 26 Tennessee Colleges of Applied Technology campuses.
- Supported and trained the Tennessee Board of Regents affiliated 13 community college and 6 university technical staff on proprietary portal and identity and access management products used by 177k+ students.
- Managed Java applications, SSL certificates, and Java KeyStores in Linux RedHat environments running on Tomcat and Weblogic.

DEVELOPMENT RESPONSIBILITIES

- Developed custom Microsoft Office 365 Mail and Calendar components for proprietary React-based web portal using provided SDK, MSAL (Microsoft Authentication Library), & Microsoft Graph APIs.
- Developed custom themes for a proprietary Liferay-based web portal using Eclipse, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, and jQuery.
- Developed custom pages for proprietary Angular-based ERP tool using Oracle SQL, CSS, and Angular.
- Developed custom JSR-286 portlets for Liferay-based web portal using Java, Spring, Ant, Maven, JSP Views, Oracle SQL, Eclipse, and MVC design paradigm.

ADDITIONAL EXPERIENCE

Full-Stack Teaching Assistant

2019 - 2021

Vanderbilt University

Nashville, TN

Engaging, empowering, and encouraging students in their journey to becoming full-stack web
developers. The course focuses on the MERN stack (MongoDB, ExpressJS, ReactJS, and NodeJS) and
computer science fundamentals. Primary responsibilities include grading submitted
homework/projects, providing one-on-one assistance with class material, and using data-driven
analytics to enhance student learning.

Full-Stack Centralized Grader & Senior Tutor

2020 - 2022

2U

Nashville, TN

 Met with students one-on-one to discuss any issues, topics, or concepts as they work through the Full Stack Web Development boot camp. This included troubleshooting and debugging projects and discussing higher-level topics like the DOM, Object-Oriented Programming, DevOps, or career-related matters.

Network Manager

2013 - 2015

Polk County School Board

Lakeland, FL

EDUCATION

Vanderbilt University | Nashville, TN | 2019

Vanderbilt University Boot Camp - Full-Stack Web Development

A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Firebase, Node.js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js & ReactJS.

Polk State College | Lakeland, FL | 2016

Network Systems Engineering Technology - Non-Degree Seeking
Obtained CompTIA A+, Cisco CCNA, and Microsoft MCP certifications

Johnson University | Knoxville, TN | 2010

Bachelor of Science in Bible, Church Music, & Worship Ministry with an emphasis in Media Production Graduated Magna Cum Laude